[
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which type of economy does India have?",
        "answer": "Mixed",
        "choices": [
            "Mixed",
            "Socialist",
            "Gandhian",
            "Free"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The main source of national income of India is",
        "answer": "Service",
        "choices": [
            "Service",
            "Manufacturing",
            "Agriculture",
            "Foreign Remittances"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "As the economy develops, the national income share of tertiary sector",
        "answer": "goes on increasing",
        "choices": [
            "goes on increasing",
            "first decreases, then increase",
            "first increase, then decrease",
            "goes on decreasing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "One of the problems in calculating National Income in India is",
        "answer": "non-organised sector",
        "choices": [
            "non-organised sector",
            "under-employment",
            "inflation",
            "low level of savings"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a method to calculate the Gross Domestic Product (GDP)?",
        "answer": "Diminishing Cost Method",
        "choices": [
            "Diminishing Cost Method",
            "Product Method",
            "Income Method",
            "Expenditure Method"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which one does not come under economic infrastructure?",
        "answer": "Education or Health",
        "choices": [
            "Education or Health",
            "Energy",
            "Roads",
            "Railway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Hindu growth is related to",
        "answer": "GDP",
        "choices": [
            "GDP",
            "Money",
            "Population",
            "GNP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "What is money?",
        "answer": "Commodity",
        "choices": [
            "Commodity",
            "Income",
            "Wealth",
            "Savings"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The economist who for the first time scientifically determined National Income in India?",
        "answer": "V K R V Rao",
        "choices": [
            "V K R V Rao",
            "D R Gadgil",
            "Manmohan Singh",
            "Y V Alagh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Who was the remarkable person who took the action for calculating the national income of India before Independence?",
        "answer": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        "choices": [
            "Dadabhai Naoroji",
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Surendranath Banerjee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which of the following offices or institutes releases data of the National Income in India?",
        "answer": "National Statistical Office (NSO)",
        "choices": [
            "National Statistical Office (NSO)",
            "National Sample Survey Office (NSSO)",
            "Central Statistical Office (CSO) ",
            "NITI Ayog"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which organisation carries out the survey for determining the poverty line?",
        "answer": "National Statistical Office (NSO)",
        "choices": [
            "National Statistical Office (NSO)",
            "National Sample Survey Office (NSSO)",
            "Reserve Bank of India (RBI)",
            "NITI Ayog"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which ministry is responsible for calculating GDP of India?",
        "answer": "Ministry of Central Statistical and Program Implementation",
        "choices": [
            "Ministry of Central Statistical and Program Implementation",
            "Ministry of Commerce and Industry",
            "Ministry of Finance",
            "Ministry of Consumer Affairs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The best index of economic income can be provided by",
        "answer": "increase in per capita real income per year",
        "choices": [
            "increase in per capita real income per year",
            "increase in national income at current price",
            "increase in savings ration",
            "improvement in balance of payment position"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Per Capita income of a country is obtained from",
        "answer": "both National Income and Population",
        "choices": [
            "both National Income and Population",
            "Population",
            "National Income",
            "GDP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The latest per capita income at constant prices is lowest for which state of India?",
        "answer": "Bihar",
        "choices": [
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Jharkhand",
            "Manipur"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The latest per capita income at constant prices is highest for which state of India?",
        "answer": "Sikkim",
        "choices": [
            "Sikkim",
            "Goa",
            "Telangana",
            "Karnataka"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which state of India has highest Gross State Domestic Product (GSDP)?",
        "answer": "Maharashtra",
        "choices": [
            "Maharashtra",
            "Karnataka",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Tamil Nadu"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which sector of Indian economy contributes the most to the Gross National Product (GNP)?",
        "answer": "Tertiary Sector",
        "choices": [
            "Tertiary Sector",
            "Secondary Sector",
            "Primary Sector",
            "Public Sector"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which organization publishes the global Sustainable Development Report (SDR)?",
        "answer": "UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network",
        "choices": [
            "UN Sustainable Development Solutions Network",
            "NITI Aayog",
            "United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)",
            "World Bank"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "As per the Sustainable Development Report (SDR) 2025, what is India's rank in the SDG Index out of 167 countries?",
        "answer": "99th",
        "choices": [
            "99th",
            "109th ",
            "112th",
            "121st"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Which Indian organization is responsible for monitoring the progress of SDGs at the sub-national level (States and UTs)?",
        "answer": "NITI Aayog",
        "choices": [
            "NITI Aayog",
            "Ministry of Finance",
            "Reserve Bank of India (RBI)",
            "Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation (MoSPI)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The SDG Index measures a country's progress towards which set of goals?",
        "answer": "17 goals",
        "choices": [
            "17 goals",
            "10 goals",
            "15 goals",
            "20 goals"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The Human Capital Index (HCI) is published by which of the following international organizations?",
        "answer": "World Bank",
        "choices": [
            "World Bank",
            "United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)",
            "World Health Organisation (WHO)",
            "International Monetary Fund (IMF)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In India, the agricultural crop year period is",
        "answer": "1st July to 30th June",
        "choices": [
            "1st July to 30th June",
            "1st June to 31st May",
            "1st April to 31st March",
            "1st January to 31st December"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "What is the theme of the Union Budget 2025-26?",
        "answer": "Sabka Vikas",
        "choices": [
            "Sabka Vikas",
            "Sabka Vikas Sabka Prayas",
            "Sabka Sath",
            "Viksit Bharat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024-25, what is the expected Real GDP growth for FY2025?",
        "answer": "6.4 percent",
        "choices": [
            "6.4 percent",
            "4.6 percent",
            "5.4 percent",
            "4.5 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024-25, what is the expected Real GVA growth for FY2025?",
        "answer": "6.4 percent",
        "choices": [
            "6.4 percent",
            "4.6 percent",
            "5.4 percent",
            "4.5 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In the Union Budget 2025-26 what are the four engines of Economic Growth?",
        "answer": "Agriculture, MSME, Investment and Exports",
        "choices": [
            "Agriculture, MSME, Investment and Exports",
            "Agriculture, Defence, Tourism, Banking",
            "Defence, Tourism, Exports, Banking",
            "Tourism, Banking, MSME, Sports"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In the Union Budget 2025-26 what are the four focus point?",
        "answer": "Poor, Youth, Farmers, Women",
        "choices": [
            "Poor, Youth, Farmers, Women",
            "Poor, Science, Tourism, Health",
            "Youth, Health, Sports, AI",
            "AI, Crypto, Energy, Infrastructure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "The quote - A country is not just its soil; a country is its people, mentioned in the Union Budget 2025–26 speech, is attributed to which Indian personality?",
        "answer": "Gurajada Appa Rao",
        "choices": [
            "Gurajada Appa Rao",
            "Rabindranath Tagore",
            "Mahatma Gandhi",
            "Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Under the broad principles of Viksit Bharat announced in the Union Budget 2025-26, what percentage of women should be engaged in economic activities?",
        "answer": "70% by 2047",
        "choices": [
            "70% by 2047",
            "60% by 2040",
            "80% by 2050",
            "50% by 2030"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In the Union Budget 2025-26 which among the following is considered as the fuel for economic growth?",
        "answer": "Reforms",
        "choices": [
            "Reforms",
            "Inclusivity",
            "Devlopment",
            "Technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In the Union Budget 2025-26 which among the following is considered as the guiding spirit for economic growth?",
        "answer": "Inclusivity",
        "choices": [
            "Inclusivity",
            "Reforms",
            "Devlopment",
            "Technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In the Union Budget 2025-26 which among the following is considered as the destination of economic growth?",
        "answer": "Viksit Bharat",
        "choices": [
            "Viksit Bharat",
            "Inclusivity",
            "Devlopment",
            "Reforms"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024–25, India’s rank in global services exports is:",
        "answer": "Seventh",
        "choices": [
            "Seventh",
            "Third",
            "Fifth",
            "Tenth"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024–25, what was the approximate size of India’s forex reserves by the end of December 2024?",
        "answer": "USD 640.3 billion",
        "choices": [
            "USD 640.3 billion",
            "USD 640.3 million",
            "USD 634.6 billion",
            "USD 652.9 million"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Budget 2025-26, how many Atal Tinkering Labs will be open in government schools?",
        "answer": 50000,
        "choices": [
            50000,
            30000,
            20000,
            10000
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024-25, what is the Labour Force Participation ratio (LFPR) of India?",
        "answer": "60.1 percent",
        "choices": [
            "60.1 percent",
            "58.2 percent",
            "57.9 percent",
            "56.0 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024-25, what is the Worker Population Ratio (WPR) of India?",
        "answer": "58.2 percent",
        "choices": [
            "58.2 percent",
            "60.1 percent",
            "57.9 percent",
            "56.0 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024-25, what is the Unemployment rate in India?",
        "answer": "3.2 percent",
        "choices": [
            "3.2 percent",
            "2.8 percent",
            "3.0 percent",
            "2.5 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "Under the six-year Mission for Aatmanirbharta in Pulses, which of the following pulses is not explicitly given special focus?",
        "answer": "Moong",
        "choices": [
            "Moong",
            "Tur",
            "Masoor",
            "Urad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Economic Survey 2024–25, which category represents the largest share of the total workforce in India?",
        "answer": "Self-employed",
        "choices": [
            "Self-employed",
            "Casual Labour",
            "Regular Wage / Salaried",
            "Unpaid Workers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Budget 2025–26, what is the revised investment and turnover limit for an enterprise to be classified as a Micro MSME?",
        "answer": "Investement up to 2.5 crore and turnover upto 10 crore",
        "choices": [
            "Investement up to 2.5 crore and turnover upto 10 crore",
            "Investement up to 1 crore and turnover upto 5 crore",
            "Investement up to 25 crore and turnover upto 100 crore",
            "Investement up to 125 crore and turnover upto 500 crore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Budget 2025–26, what is the revised investment and turnover limit for an enterprise to be classified as a Small MSME?",
        "answer": "Investement up to 25 crore and turnover upto 100 crore",
        "choices": [
            "Investement up to 25 crore and turnover upto 100 crore",
            "Investement up to 10 crore and turnover upto 50 crore",
            "Investement up to 5 crore and turnover upto 10 crore",
            "Investement up to 125 crore and turnover upto 500 crore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "According to the Union Budget 2025–26, what is the revised investment and turnover limit for an enterprise to be classified as a Medium MSME?",
        "answer": "Investement up to 125 crore and turnover upto 500 crore",
        "choices": [
            "Investement up to 125 crore and turnover upto 500 crore",
            "Investement up to 50 crore and turnover upto 250 crore",
            "Investement up to 25 crore and turnover upto 100 crore",
            "Investement up to 2.5 crore and turnover upto 10 crore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "UnionEconomy",
        "question": "In the Union Budget 2024–25, which ministry received the highest budget allocation?",
        "answer": "Ministry of Defense",
        "choices": [
            "Ministry of Defense",
            "Ministry of Agriuculture & Farmers Welfare",
            "Ministry of Railways",
            "Ministry of Education"
        ]
    }
]